### sonialahcene.com

linkedin.com/sonialahcene contact@sonialahcene.com +44 (0) 7977 693 635

## Senior Digital Designer & Design Manager

I am a passionate Senior Digital Designer and Design Manager with years of experience leading creative projects from conceptualisation to completion and designing for websites and apps. Very organised and self-motivated, I love the challenge of making complex things feel simple!



### LONDON, UK

Interested in fully remote opportunities



### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Web design

Creative direction

•

Project management

Team management

• eCommerce

Communications



#### **SKILLS & SOFTWARE**

Creative • Self-driven • Analytical

UX/UI • Illustration • Infographic • Branding • Image compositing

Adobe XD • Sketch •
Photoshop • Illustrator •
InDesign

HTML • CSS

AEM (Adobe Experience Manager) • JIRA • Confluence • Visual Studio Code

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **QVC UK, LONDON**

In charge of the accurate and timely production of QVC's digital platforms, creating a seamless experience for millions of customers. From Digital Designer to Design Manager, my role at QVC has quickly evolved into a more strategic position with increased responsibilities.

### Digital Design Manager (2018 - Present)

- Leading the creative direction of digital content for the website, apps and marketing emails. Design review and sign-off of all digital assets.
- Managing and mentoring a team of Digital Designers and Web Publishers. Coordinating and prioritising work. Recruiting and training new team members.
- Overseeing platform upgrades and app releases, liaising with product owners and engineering teams, establishing roadmaps and defining best practices for content production.
- Implemented QVC new branding on digital platforms: created design guidelines and assets libraries, improving consistency and increasing productivity, while allowing flexibility and creativity for the designers.
- Documenting processes and best practices in the team's wiki (CMS module guide, design workflows, onboarding guides, etc.).
- Improving workflows and processes for the eCommerce and Design teams (JIRA training, improved briefs, best practices, etc.).
- Designing web pages and digital assets for campaigns and high-profile brands.

### Lead Digital Designer (2017-2018)

- Designed and built major cross-platform digital campaigns (Christmas, Black Friday, Holiday Shop, etc.).
- Created UX documentation, photo briefs and assets used across all platforms and channels.
- Mentored other designers and led creative direction.
- Improved Design team's productivity by creating Photoshop templates.
- Streamlined work processes (new file naming convention, JIRA functionalities, etc.).
- Helped recruit new Designers and Publishers. Trained new team members.
- Deputised for the Design Manager until being promoted Manager.

#### Digital Designer (2017)

- Created high-quality assets for the Home, Garden and Electronics departments
- Designed, built and published web pages in AEM.
- Elaborated conceptual briefs for the in-house photo studio.

### SONIA L CREATION, LTD

### Freelance Graphic Designer (2015-2017)

Offered graphic design and design consulting services for renowned brands and digital agencies.

- Key areas of expertise: graphic and digital design, illustration and design consulting.
- Brands and agencies: Timberland / GE / LinkedIn / Hootsuite / Brands2Life / The Story Lab / Mediablaze Group / Kaplan / Le Robert



### Senior Digital Designer & Design Manager



### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor in Visual Arts (2012)

University Panthéon Sorbonne Paris, France Visual Art, History of Art, Philosophy of Art

# Master in Management (2007-2011)

EDHEC Business School Lille, France Focus in Marketing and Communications



### **LANGUAGES**

English

French

• • •

Spanish

• • 0 0



### **INTERESTS**

Baking baguettes

•

T-shirt design

Doodling

Doing backflips on trampolines

### LADBROKES, LONDON

### Web & Graphic Designer (2015-2016)

- Designed and built two Google Sites for the Security & Compliance and Enterprise Architecture teams.
- Developed the branding and visual identity of both projects.
- Designed merchandising items and communication materials.

### ORANGE LABS UK, LONDON

### Communications Executive (2012-2014)

- Responsible for the internal and external communication strategy.
- Developed new branding: logos, visual assets, communication materials.
- Designed and built Orange Labs' website (EZ Publish CMS).
- Created and managed Orange Labs' intranet using Wordpress (HTML/CSS).
- Designed merchandising items for events.

### LOUIS VUITTON, PARIS

### Corporate Press Officer (2011)

- Organised a press trip for journalists from Korea, Hong Kong and Taiwan to visit Louis Vuitton's new luxury leather goods workshop in France.
- Supervised press kits production with in-house creatives and design agencies.
- Oversaw two press days and presented Louis Vuitton publications to journalists.
- Edited press reviews, gathered and analysed media alerts.
- Assisted PR officers on various projects and events.

### ALLIANCE FRANÇAISE, WASHINGTON DC

### Communication Assistant & Event Coordinator (2009-2010)

- Coordinated more than a hundred cultural events (screenings, concerts, theatre plays, festivals, etc.).
- Led a cross-promotion collaboration with the Corcoran Gallery in Washington DC.
- Maintained the website and designed promotional materials for events.
- Helped produce events by suggesting artists and negotiating their fees.
- Negotiated low rates for technical equipment and lodging for groups of artists.
- Produced reports on the trends and evolution of the cultural department (attendance, visibility, accounting).

### **VISIT MY WEBSITE**

### sonialahcene.com

